<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Prof. Annappa B</title>
    <link>//chanin.tech/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Prof. Annappa B</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="//chanin.tech/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>//chanin.tech/test/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//chanin.tech/test/</guid>
      <description>Title</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>//chanin.tech/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//chanin.tech/about/</guid>
      <description>I am Annappa B, a passionate educator, researcher, and innovator in the field of Computer Science and Engineering. With a diverse academic journey and over 25 years of experience in teaching and research, I have had the privilege to contribute to various areas of computer science, especially in cloud computing, big data analytics, distributed computing, software engineering, and process mining.
I began my academic pursuits at the Govt. U.B.D.T. College of Engineering, Davangere, where I earned my B.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Awards</title>
      <link>//chanin.tech/awards/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//chanin.tech/awards/</guid>
      <description>Best Ph.D. thesis supervisor award from BiTES, Bangalore for the year 2018 and 2020. First Rank with Institute Gold Medal in M.Tech. from N.I.T.K. Surathkal. Five Best paper awards for the research papers presented in international conferences in India and Abroad. Certificate of achievement awarded as the proctor of the Team &amp;ldquo;WhereIsMyChar&amp;rdquo; represented by Ashwin Joisa, Naveen Kumar, Shanthanu Rai from N.I.T.K Surathkal for achieving a Global Rank of 18 in IEEEXtreme 13.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>//chanin.tech/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//chanin.tech/contact/</guid>
      <description>📝
Prof Annappa B
Professor,
Department of Computer Science and Engineering,
National Institute of Technology Karnataka, Surathkal,
Mangalore, India - 575025
💻
annappa[at]nitk[dot]edu[dot]in annappa[at]ieee[dot]org
☎️
+91-824-2473401 +91-9845715006
📠
+91-824-2474056
Author Identifiers:
Google Scholar ORCID SCOPUS ResearchGate Web of Science You can also connect with me at the following social platforms:
LinkedIn </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DISCOVER Lab @ NITK</title>
      <link>//chanin.tech/lab/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//chanin.tech/lab/</guid>
      <description>My research is on Cloud, Edge &amp;amp; Distrubuted Computing, Computer Vision Applications, Explainable AI &amp;amp; Federated learning. I lead the DISCOVER Lab - Distributed Computing and Vision Inteligence Research - at CSE, NITK.
Current Students Manjunatha S H, PhD Student. Saraswati Koppad, PhD Student. Rashmi Adyapady, PhD Student. Shubham Dodia, PhD Student. Aarabhi Putti, PhD Student. Sachin D N, PhD Student. Satish Ambesenge, PhD Student. Sneha H R, PhD Student. Naveen Kumar M R, PhD Student.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Invited Talks</title>
      <link>//chanin.tech/talks/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//chanin.tech/talks/</guid>
      <description>2023 Invited talk on “Federated Learning and Explainable AI” (on June 2023) during the Seven-Days SERB Sponsored high-end workshop titled &amp;ldquo;Distributed Intelligence: Convergence of AI and distributed computing systems&amp;rdquo;. IIIT Kottayam, Kerala. Invited lecture on “Explainable AI”, on March 2023 organised by Vidyavardhaka College of Engineering, Mysuru. 2022 Invited lecture on “DIGITAL TECHNOLOGIES FOR OLDER PERSONS AND HEALTHY AGEING”, on May 24, 2022 organised by The Institution of Engineers (India) Mangaluru Local Centre on the occasion of WORLD TELECOMMUNICATION AND INFORMATION SOCIETY DAY - 2022.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Publications</title>
      <link>//chanin.tech/publications/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//chanin.tech/publications/</guid>
      <description>2023 KAC segnet: a novel kernel based active contour method for lung nodule segmentation and classification using dense alexnet framework
S Dodia, B Annappa, PA Mahesh
International Journal of Information Technology &amp;amp; Decision Making	2023
Classification of Skin Cancer Images using Lightweight Convolutional Neural Network
TS Kumar, B Annappa, S Dodia
2023 4th International Conference for Emerging Technology (INCET), 1-6
YARS-IDS: A Novel IDS For Multi-Class Classification
Yash Madwanna, B Annappa, HR Sneha</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Service</title>
      <link>//chanin.tech/service/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//chanin.tech/service/</guid>
      <description>Technical Program Committee, IEEE International Conference on Blockchain and Distributed Systems Security, IIIT Naya Raipur (2023). General Chair, 2nd IEEE International Conference on Data, Decision and Systems, NITK, Surathkal (2023). Organizing chair, 7th IEEE International Conference on Recent Advances and Innovations in Engineering, NITK, Surathkal (2022). Branch Counsellor, NITK-IEEE Student Branch (Current). Visiting Professor, Université des Mascareignes, Mauritius (2017-2018). Chair (2018), IEEE Mangalore subsection. Chair (2017-18), IEEE Computer Society Chapter, India Council.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sponsored R &amp; D Projects</title>
      <link>//chanin.tech/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//chanin.tech/projects/</guid>
      <description>Ongoing Chief Investigator for Sponserd Project &amp;ldquo;Automatic early Detection of Lung Cancer from LDCT Images based on Deep Neural Networks&amp;rdquo;. 30 Lakhs, 2023. Chief Investigator for project &amp;ldquo;Knowledge Partner for Cloud Development and Architecture&amp;rdquo;, Tata Consultancy Services(TCS)-iON, 21.68 Lakhs, 2022-24 Co-cordinator for ISRO-RESPOND sponsored R&amp;amp;D project “Customized reconfigurable platform for Image/Video compression based on deep learning algorithms for hyperspectral Image”, sanctioned with the financial outlay of ₹29,34,880/-, 2021-2023. Completed Coordinator for MHRD sponsored R&amp;amp;D project on “Design and evaluation of an object oriented verification approach for Distributed Systems”, completed the project which had financial outlay of ₹12 lakhs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Subject Taught</title>
      <link>//chanin.tech/teaching/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//chanin.tech/teaching/</guid>
      <description> Cloud Computing. Data Science. Distributed Systems. Operating Systems. Web Technology. Software System Design and Architecture. Object oriented analysis and design. Database Management systems. Management Information Systems. Software Engineering. Computer programming with C. Data Structures. Distributed databases. Object oriented programming with C++ &amp;amp; Java </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
